<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mr. Abar</title>
    <link>https://mrabar.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mr. Abar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 15:36:13 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mrabar.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DevOpsCon 2023</title>
      <link>https://mrabar.me/posts/devopscon-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 15:36:13 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrabar.me/posts/devopscon-23/</guid>
      <description>Intro I have attended a DevOps Conference in Berlin and here I will try to summarize my experience and outtakes from it.
This hybrid conference was located &amp;ndash; physically &amp;ndash; in the heart of Berlin, at Martim Hotel near Friedrichstraße S-Bahn station. That location was very well known to me, because it was a changing station from when I went from my university to my work. So, visiting it again after several years was pleasant and nostalgic, and I&amp;rsquo;m, glad that not much has changed there - not for the worst, at least.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I have a strong opinion about new .zip domains!</title>
      <link>https://mrabar.me/posts/zip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 23:37:42 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrabar.me/posts/zip/</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip; &amp;hellip;but I will not express it here, because this is a all-age-appropriate blog.
Let&amp;rsquo;s review new top-level domains that Google announced. Just to know what&amp;rsquo;s in store.
.dad domain &amp;ndash; it may be good for that one site for dad jokes, I guess? .esq, .prof, .phd &amp;ndash; not gonna judge; if I&amp;rsquo;d had a doctorate, I&amp;rsquo;d probably want a domain to scream about this fact to the world too. .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In reply to: Clean Code Horrible Performance</title>
      <link>https://mrabar.me/posts/clean-code-good-enough-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 16:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrabar.me/posts/clean-code-good-enough-performance/</guid>
      <description>Intro I recently stumbled across a talk &amp;ldquo;Clean&amp;rdquo; Code, Horrible Performance by Casey Muratori. He makes a great point, and I invite my readers like crawlers or searchbots, because no one else visits me to give him a visit and at least glance over the transcript.
In his talk, mr. Muratori implements a classic example of &amp;ldquo;find the area of a various geometric shapes&amp;rdquo; in C++ using all the best practices from Clean Code recommendations, measures the performance, and then demonstrates how to improve benchmarks by violating one or several principles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devternity 2021</title>
      <link>https://mrabar.me/posts/devternity2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 10:11:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrabar.me/posts/devternity2021/</guid>
      <description>Intro Before going to DevTernity 2021 I had no expectations of what might be in there. It was just another conference that was forwarded to me by my manager, and I was just bored enough to decide to sign up for it. I haven&amp;rsquo;t checked the backgrounds of the presenters and wasn&amp;rsquo;t even aware that Uncle Bob himself will give a talk there.
During the conference, I was amazed by the technical level of presenters and the potential usefulness of the reports.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legacy migration: custom request handling in Spring Web</title>
      <link>https://mrabar.me/posts/legacy_handling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 21:10:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrabar.me/posts/legacy_handling/</guid>
      <description>Intro If one day you woke up with the feeling, that the standard Spring Web handlers are lacking functionality and you want to extend it yourself, then look no further. This article is for you, and I hope it will be helpful.
Example Consider the scenario: you have an old legacy project full of heavy domain logic and questionable technical solutions. Logic is grouped by so called modules, each module may have one or several action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IT_ONE: Java and Big Data Meet Up</title>
      <link>https://mrabar.me/posts/it_one_2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 09:30:25 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrabar.me/posts/it_one_2021/</guid>
      <description>My synopsis + English translation for IT_One Meet Up - a free online meetup for Java and Big Data.
Overview of big data storage tech. Pros-, Cons-, how to use. By Maksim Stacenko
Topics:
Describing technologies, highlighting how to save date engineer time by choosing not the most popular solutions Share experience from PoC works on big data Saving on hardware
Your data storage is a product: do you store test data only, do you use it in production, does it working 24/7 (especially with the new remote work approach), do you remember the legal consequences of neglecting data safety and consistency?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$2,000 and 3rd Rank Winner of the MicroStream Hackathon</title>
      <link>https://mrabar.me/posts/microstream_hackaton/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 21:43:51 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrabar.me/posts/microstream_hackaton/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random links</title>
      <link>https://mrabar.me/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 21:37:53 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrabar.me/links/</guid>
      <description> https://berthub.eu/articles/posts/how-tech-loses-out/ https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2002/01/06/fire-and-motion/ https://docs.google.com/document/d/10JkELEYxLtQuU1JwHf9CXKvlV3csSX6QAoF5lXXBbWk https://mark-skidmore.com/2021/11/06/dr-peter-doshis-remarkable-speech-everybody-knows/ </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JPoint 2020</title>
      <link>https://mrabar.me/posts/jpoint-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 17:49:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrabar.me/posts/jpoint-2020/</guid>
      <description>Microservices made easy with MicroProfile OpenJ9 Open Liberty and OpenShift Presented by Jamie Coleman.
MicroProfile - OS-commnity specification for Enterprise Java microservices; A community of individuals, organizations and vendors, collaborating within an open souce platform.
MicroProfile vendors/implementations: OpenLiberty, MicroPayara, Thorntail, Apache TomEE, Hammock, kumuluzEE.
MicroProfile 3.3 stack: Open Tracing, Health Check, Metrics, Open API, Fault Tolerante, JWT Propagation, Config, JAX-RS, CDI, JSON-P, JSON-B, Rest Client.
JAX-RS: @Path, CDI: @Inject, JSON-B / -P: @Consumer(MediaType.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joker 2020. Days 3 &amp; 4.</title>
      <link>https://mrabar.me/posts/joker-2020-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 16:41:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrabar.me/posts/joker-2020-2/</guid>
      <description>Hidden pearls for high-performance-persistence in Java Presented by Sven Ruppert - DevSecOps from JFrog.
Presentation was pre-recorder, but the questions were live.
Why and what: Inside of JVM, for different areas - from embedded, to terabyte-big document storage systems, but scaling and tuning ways of storing data.
You can&amp;rsquo;t get rid of the persistence layer, but there are three solutions as the beginning of making optimization.
JOOQ: a tool for mapping SQL to Java DSL - SQL style, generated from the DB schema.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joker 2020. Days 1 &amp; 2.</title>
      <link>https://mrabar.me/posts/joker-2020-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 16:41:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrabar.me/posts/joker-2020-1/</guid>
      <description>Spring: Your next Java microframework Presented by Alexey Nesterov. First time presented in the Russian language.
Using Spring as micro-framework. Microframework: often is specifically designed for building the APIs for another service or application. In microframeworks, people typically seek ease of development, speed, simplicity, cloud-readiness (cloud-native).
Spring easy.
(&amp;hellip;to develop)
Autoconfigs, profiles, etc. No Livereload? There is livereload for Spring! Spring Boot Dev Tools: livereload, works even remotely + tons of other features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Certifications</title>
      <link>https://mrabar.me/posts/certifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 22:48:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrabar.me/posts/certifications/</guid>
      <description>This is a stub, on a Russian version of this blog you may read a post in which I analyze the following certifications: 1Z0-808 1Z0-819 1Z0-909 1Z0-071 RHCSA If you are interested in what I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about those certifications and their requirements - feel free to go there. If you are interested in learning more about said certifications - then I can only advise you to follow the links and read info from the original sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nordic Testing Days 2019</title>
      <link>https://mrabar.me/posts/ntd19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 12:32:37 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrabar.me/posts/ntd19/</guid>
      <description>Full-day tutorial Efficient Selenium Infrastructure with Selenoid.
The most insightful tutorial for me. Was lead by a really cool specialist, who works daily with Highload in testing infrastructure. Unfortunately, the tutorial went slowly and didn&amp;rsquo;t cover all the topics presenter hoped to cover, because of the low preparation level from participants.
Honorable mentions: Resilience Testing: Let the chaos begin! Presenters went over basics of Gattling and introduced a Chaos Monkey. Once again, the audience wasn&amp;rsquo;t prepared for it, and we were stuck in the first step with setting up VMs and launching Gatling scenarios.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running manual Cucumber tests in Java</title>
      <link>https://mrabar.me/posts/manual-cucumber/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrabar.me/posts/manual-cucumber/</guid>
      <description>In theory, it would be nice to have everything automated. In reality, it might be the case that for some reasons you have to run and manually verify test results.
There can be a number of ways for running manual Cucumber tests, for Ruby there&amp;rsquo;s even whole CukeHub to run and organize manual tests, but my research yielded no results on how to do manual testing in Java.
So, let&amp;rsquo;s implement it our self.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
