<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>conferences on Mr. Abar</title>
    <link>https://mrabar.me/categories/conferences/</link>
    <description>Recent content in conferences on Mr. Abar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 17:49:51 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mrabar.me/categories/conferences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>JPoint 2020</title>
      <link>https://mrabar.me/posts/jpoint-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 17:49:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrabar.me/posts/jpoint-2020/</guid>
      <description>Microservices made easy with MicroProfile OpenJ9 Open Liberty and OpenShift Presented by Jamie Coleman.
MicroProfile - OS-commnity specification for Enterprise Java microservices; A community of individuals, organizations and vendors, collaborating within an open souce platform.
MicroProfile vendors/implementations: OpenLiberty, MicroPayara, Thorntail, Apache TomEE, Hammock, kumuluzEE.
MicroProfile 3.3 stack: Open Tracing, Health Check, Metrics, Open API, Fault Tolerante, JWT Propagation, Config, JAX-RS, CDI, JSON-P, JSON-B, Rest Client.
JAX-RS: @Path, CDI: @Inject, JSON-B / -P: @Consumer(MediaType.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joker 2020. Days 3 &amp; 4.</title>
      <link>https://mrabar.me/posts/joker-2020-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 16:41:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrabar.me/posts/joker-2020-2/</guid>
      <description>Hidden pearls for high-performance-persistence in Java Presented by Sven Ruppert - DevSecOps from JFrog.
Presentation was pre-recorder, but the questions were live.
Why and what: Inside of JVM, for different areas - from embedded, to terabyte-big document storage systems, but scaling and tuning ways of storing data.
You can&amp;rsquo;t get rid of the persistence layer, but there are three solutions as the beginning of making optimization.
JOOQ: a tool for mapping SQL to Java DSL - SQL style, generated from the DB schema.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joker 2020. Days 1 &amp; 2.</title>
      <link>https://mrabar.me/posts/joker-2020-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 16:41:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrabar.me/posts/joker-2020-1/</guid>
      <description>Spring: Your next Java microframework Presented by Alexey Nesterov. First time presented in the Russian language.
Using Spring as micro-framework. Microframework: often is specifically designed for building the APIs for another service or application. In microframeworks, people typically seek ease of development, speed, simplicity, cloud-readiness (cloud-native).
Spring easy.
(&amp;hellip;to develop)
Autoconfigs, profiles, etc. No Livereload? There is livereload for Spring! Spring Boot Dev Tools: livereload, works even remotely + tons of other features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nordic Testing Days 2019</title>
      <link>https://mrabar.me/posts/ntd19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 12:32:37 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrabar.me/posts/ntd19/</guid>
      <description>Full-day tutorial Efficient Selenium Infrastructure with Selenoid.
The most insightful tutorial for me. Was lead by a really cool specialist, who works daily with Highload in testing infrastructure. Unfortunately, the tutorial went slowly and didn&amp;rsquo;t cover all the topics presenter hoped to cover, because of the low preparation level from participants.
Honorable mentions: Resilience Testing: Let the chaos begin! Presenters went over basics of Gattling and introduced a Chaos Monkey. Once again, the audience wasn&amp;rsquo;t prepared for it, and we were stuck in the first step with setting up VMs and launching Gatling scenarios.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
